HARIS MUHAMMAD

Contact

(248) 686-6101 hello@harism.dev github.com/harismh Detroit, MI

Technical Skills

TypeScript
Python
Clojure
ClojureScript
React
React Native
Expo
HTML5
CSS3
PostgresSQL

AWS, Heroku, Vercel Node, Deno, Bun Linux, Unix Docker PyTorch TensorFlow Agile, Scrum CI/CD, DevOps

Git, GitHub, GitLab

Education

B.S. Computer Science Western Governors University 3.9 GPA, 2024

References

Tyler Martin CEO, FLIP (248) 877-2992 tyler@flip.app

Justin Kramer Former CTO, FLIP (607) 351-2372 jkkramer@gmail.com

About

I am a Software Engineer with over **8** years of experience launching products, leading development teams, and building scalable apps used by millions of users. My expertise spans technical leadership, full stack development, data analytics and presentation, API design and integrations, and security auditing and vulnerability analysis. With a deep understanding of client- and server-side technologies, and enterprise and customer-facing systems, I am confident in my ability to grow, lead, take ownership, and deliver from concept to release.

Experience

Chief Technology Officer FLIP (JIT Learning Platform, flip.cards) — 2021-2024

- Directed several application launches for multiple enterprise clients, including audit and accounting firms such as Deloitte, Forvis Mazars, and Grant Thornton, automotive like Mazda, Stellantis, GM, and Ford, and the US Air Force. Active users totaled over 1.5 million with average satisfaction ratings at 4.5 out of 5.
 Leveraged TypeScript, React/Native, Node, and Postgres.
- Partnered with Deloitte and created a COVID-19 safety training program
 reaching over 600K employees worldwide within 1 month, all while providing
 demonstrable learner and regulatory compliance. This project, among other
 initiatives, earned 2 Gold Awards in Excellence in Technology from Brandon
 Hall. Leveraged TypeScript, React/Native, and Postgres.
- Pioneered a 6-month effort to rebuild the entire development toolchain, eliminating 9.5 million lines of branch code, unifying 30 customer apps into one common base, accelerating deployments 100x, and dropping launch times from several days to minutes. Accomplished with Git, Github CI/CD, Heroku, Expo, and a custom-built CLI.
- Architected a custom SSO authentication module enabling seamless, secure logins across multiple enterprise tenants, eliminating a major business bottleneck and generating over \$500K in new sales with 0 increase in hosting costs. Created with TypeScript, Node, and Postgres.
- Built an analytics platform providing real-time insights into 100+ learning and
 performance metrics while delivering sub-second exports, automated email
 alerts, and syncing with external data lakes. The solution is "a game changer,"
 as one customer stakeholder put it, using it for all of their worldwide initiatives.
 Created with Typescript, React/Native, Node, Postgres, and a custom-made
 event log and transducer logic.
- Overhauled all technical docs, lowering new developer onboarding times by 75%, from 1 month to 1 week. One developer praised the new docs as "an incredible productivity booster." Used Notion, Basecamp, and GitHub.

Client Development Lead FLIP — 2020-2021

Full Stack React Developer FLIP — 2019-2020